Roberto C. Gomez

Edinburg, Texas, United States



robertogcanelo12@gmail.com



9564574229



linkedin.com/in/roberto-c-gomez-86a735b6

Summary

My passion for coding is new to my world. I never pictured myself in the tech field, but here I am a few experiences later, full-filling a fire inside me to create beautiful works of art through coding.

I've had several career paths and I realized my love for coding after being a technology teacher. I found myself reaching out to the program creators asking how they came up with the idea or what lead them to find the creativity in designing said program.

Now coding and trading full-time has helped me find my own happiness and also helped me find the love in the work that I do.

Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript(E6), Node.js

Experience



Full Stack Engineer

Freelance

Oct 2021 - Present (4 months +)

Develop full-stack web applications that process, analyze, and render data visually.

Liaised with back-end developers, front-end developers, and project managers.

Manage time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades.

Plan, write and debug web applications and software with complete accuracy.



Technology Specialist

Edinburg cisd

Aug 2019 - Jan 2021 (1 year 6 months)

- · Support the goals, philosophy, and mission of the district
- Establish and maintain effective relationships with students, parents, and colleagues
- Communicate effectively with students, parents, and colleagues
- Promote a positive learning environment that includes behavioral management techniques appropriate to the needs of all students
- Plan, develop, and evaluate lessons for basic computer, keyboard, and internet skills to students in Kindergarten through Grade 6
- Develop lessons that include differentiation techniques
- Integrate the core content objectives in lessons as much as possible
- Teach internet safety including personal responsibility for technology use
- Facilitate and inspire student learning and creativity
- · Assist students in connecting to technological principles in the real world
- Keep abreast of developments in the technology field by reading literature/journals, talking with colleagues, and professional development

- Evaluate and grade students' class work, assignments, projects, etc.
- Maintain and monitor student usage of computer lab equipment
- Be aware of and monitor internet usage for students as outlined by District policy
- Work collaboratively with the Digital Learning Coach and other technology teachers to continually develop effective lesson plans using technology
- Collaborate with the building principal on technology updates
- Assist in the maintenance and upkeep of the computer lab materials
- Perform duties assigned by the administration in accordance with district policies, practices, and procedures and the negotiated agreement
- Work collaboratively with the other staff members in the building to assist them with educational technology needs
- Develop innovative lessons to challenge 21st century learners
- Follow all standard procedures as outlined in the District Teacher Job Description

QMHP-Case Manager

Tropical Texas Behavioral Health

Apr 2016 - Feb 2017 (11 months)

- Provides and administers Skills Training by conducting individual and family sessions in accordance to the Uniform Assessment as presented in the Texas Resilience and Recovery (TRR) approach.
- •Conducts routine and crisis screenings to determine need for psychiatric in-patient hospitalization, admission into Center services, assists in crisis prevention and management by locating and coordinating service and supports.
- •Performs minimally complex social service work and ensures health care services as needed to clients. Conducts home visits.
- •Facilitates and arranges for the communication of information between clients to psychiatric and community services.
- Work under moderate supervision with latitude for the use of initiative and independent judgment.



Social Studies Tutor

Sylvan Learning

Feb 2016 - Jul 2016 (6 months)

- •We will provide personalized instruction in Reading, Math, Writing, Study Skills, SAT/ACT Prep, TSI, and homework support
- •Provide students with instant feedback and recognition
- Evaluate and document student progress
- •Inspire Students: Develop rapport with students and establish a fun learning environment
- •Maintain a positive attitude and demonstrate enthusiasm for teaching at Sylvan



Old Navy

Nov 2014 - Feb 2015 (4 months)

Seasonal cashier and floors attendant with providing excellent customer service.

Student Tutor

Edinburg Consolidated Independent School District

Aug 2011 - Jun 2012 (11 months)

Tasked with helping students who were in need of help in a specific area of education. Major areas I tutored were biology, chemistry, algebra 2, calculus 1, and foreign language (Spanish). I was also responsible for creating specific tutoring regiments for students to accustom to their specific need of help.

Education

Full-Stack Web Development, Tech Oct 2021 - Mar 2022

The University of Texas at San Antonio

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Psychology 2012 - Jun 2015

The University of Texas Rio Grande Valley

Bachelor's degree, Accounting 2018 - 2019 Currently working on my second bachelors degree in accounting!

The University of Texas-Pan American

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Psychology 2010 - 2012

Licenses & Certifications

Introduction to Programming Using HTML and CSS - Lambda School 6177a9cd4d6d102921380d76

Skills

HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • Quality, Health, Safety, and Environment (QHSE) • Research • Analysis • Sales • Project Management • Project Planning • Budgets